Nivedha Kuppuram



Summary

Passionate Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in developing web applications and back-end systems. Expertise in software development frameworks and SDLC methodologies, such as Agile, Scrum, or Waterfall. Familiarity with software testing and quality assurance techniques, including unit testing, integration testing, and continuous integration and delivery.

Work Experience

Software Engineer

Dec 2021 - Present

Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd

Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Led the design and development of multilingual web applications such as Saudia Airlines and Huggies, driving \$7 billion of revenue every year using the latest technologies of C#, .NET, Sitecore Headless, Azure, SQL Server and Web Services.
- Designed and implemented scalable Web Services to acquire lawyer details, passenger details from CMS using .NET Core, Sitecore indexing and Databases that retrieves millions of requests daily within 10 seconds.
- Integrated Coveo search with Sitecore Headless architecture and developed search indexing which increased content delivery by 70%. Created custom solr indexing and utilized to develop Web Services.
- Incorporated scripts using C# and PowerShell to migrate data for site's architecture upgradation.
- Utilized Jira to provide a continuous integration service and to automate workflows, configured to manage multiple projects and customized as ticketing tool.
- Tech Stack: C#, ASP.NET MVC, .NET framework 4.6v, LINQ, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MSSQL, Sitecore Headless Architecture, PowerShell, Sitecore Serialization and Azure Devops

Associate Software Engineer

Nov 2020 - Nov 2021

Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd

Chennai. Tamilnadu

- Developed a scalable and dynamic ecommerce based web applications using ASP.NET MVC which depends on Sitecore Helix architecture with .NET framework of 4.7v.
- Utilized Sitecore CMS to authorize and manage content, Azure Devops to provide CI/CD in order to automate the entire process of loading the latest build code and test files.
- Integrated Bazaarvoice and Google Tag Manager (DataLayer) to track the site and trending articles based on the user actions engaging experiences that drives ecommerce traffic.
- Lead engineer for designing and developing the automatic password generator with complex requirements with encryption and decryption technology that provides the user to create an account at ease.
- Increased traffic by 52% by refactoring and optimising the site performance which increases global revenue approximately \$1.3K per month.
- Tech Stack: C#, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Core, WinForms .NET framework 4.7v, MSSQL, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Sitecore Helix and Azure Devops.

PROJECTS

Portfolio Design Portfolio-Design

Designed and developed responsive portfolio website which is compatible in all devices and viewports including highlights of animation and theme toggle.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Auto-Password Generator

Password-Generator

Developed automatic password generator tool to create a secured and encrypted password with complex requirements at ease. Increased efficiency from 75% to 97%.

Tech Stack: C#, VS Console

Mortgage Calculator

Mortgage-calculator

Designed and developed a interactive and responsive web application which computes interest rate per month, total tenure and total loan amount estimation.

Tech Stack: ASP.NET MVC, C#, .NET framework 4.6.2, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

SKILLS

- C# | .NET | OOP | ASP.NET MVC
- MSSQL | MYSQL
- HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery
- LINQ | JSON | XML
- Unit Testing | Selenium

- Frontend | Backend | Full-Stack
- Sitecore Helix | Headless | PowerShell
- Azure Devops | CI/CD | Git | Jira | Jenkins
- Figma | Adobe XD | Wireframes | Postman | BitBucket

Notable Certifications

- Sitecore 10 .NET Developer
- SC-900: Microsoft Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals
- PL-900: Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals
- Introduction to Cybersecurity
- .NET Developer
- AZ-204: Azure Developer Associate
- AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

AWARDS

Skill Star Award

Awarded the 2023 Accenture Celebrates Excellence in the Skill Start Award Category for accomplishing unique, distinctive and impactful results by delivering on the promise of technology and human ingenuity.

Sparkling Star Award

Awarded the Sparkling Star Award from 2020-2022 for high-performance and contributions by DU Leads.

EDUCATION

2020 Electronics and Communication Engineering at Saveetha Engineering College (GPA: 8.24/10)

2016 Class 12th State Board

(83.4%)